Chapter 3: Tom Riddle and Defense Class

note: Bellatrix Black is a contemporary of Tom Riddle in this story.

Chapter Three – Tom Riddle and Defense Class

Professor Merrythought was of the opinion that in order to be a true warrior, you needed discipline in everything you do: be precise with everything, from the way you draw your wand, to the way you brush your teeth.

Tom agreed fully with her on this point. Discipline made you learn self-control, made you harder and stronger. Discipline makes you more dangerous.

Tom forced himself to practice constant vigilance. Even now, before anyone else had arrived to Defense, he scanned the room deeply, not just with his eyes, but also feeling for any hint of hidden magics.

Probably at one point, the professor had held herself to the high standard she liked to stress. It was clear that her passion for battle had left her years ago, but her knowledge and insight never would. At least she had a clue what she was talking about. She also appreciated and rewarded enthusiasm and competence in her classes, unlike most teachers, who didn't seem to care one way or the other.

Truly, he didn't really like Professor Merrythought much. If only the hypocrite still practiced what she preached. It was obvious that she had in fact done some of the amazing feats years past - she often gloated them - but just as obviously, her days of slaying Inferi were over. If only teachers took these things a little more seriously, perhaps the students wouldn't be so incompetent...

She was certainly no Tobo Mott. Tom had learned far better lessons on how to stay alive in Mott's "extra-curricular activities" than any Ministry-approved Defence Against the Dark Arts class he had taken at Hogwarts. Tobo Mott was a man Tom could appreciate. He didn't look forward to the end of their "lessons" together, when he'd have to cast Tobo Mott down and Obliviate him into oblivion, or, more than likely, kill him. But the man knew far too much of what Tom was capable. Not to mention, my payment for his lessons...

He did, however, look forward to the day when Headmaster Dippet would invite Tom into his office with a smile on his face. He would watch the crushing defeat in Galatea Merrythought's eyes when Dippet thanked her for her near 50 years of service, and informed her that Tom Riddle had shown the competence and aptitude worthy of usurping her position.

Tom would enjoy that victory very much.

The Professor managed to walk in right as class was scheduled to start. Tom caught himself from visibly frowning.

She had been frequently late as of this term; she kept misplacing crucial things, it would seem. Things like her lesson plans, or her glasses, or her shoes. The students spoke during mealtimes of how forgetful she seemed.

Tom hoped there had been a time when she would have gone above and beyond to cast wards to protect her living quarters from intrusion. But clearly that time had passed, as he had little trouble bypassing the superficial detection charms she lazily placed.

For now these little dings in her reputation would do: late for class three times already this week due to misplacing things or having small "accidents". I have a funny feeling there's going to be an urgent personal issue to force her to miss a few days of classes coming up...

Soon enough, people would start expecting her to mess things up more often, including herself. That unsure confidence would fester and cause her to get sloppier without Tom's further assistance. Gently prod her in the direction of failure, and she'll walk straight into it. Dippet will not be pleased...

Taking her seat, Professor Merrythought ruffled through her papers, all out of order, for some reason, this morning.

Tom had been quite careful to not so much as glance as them when he had rearranged today's lesson. He didn't have a moral problem with cheating, but he did have his own strange principles. His purpose was just to make Merrythought look bad, and if he took advantage of his strategies to, in this case for example, learn the lesson ahead of time, it would just make him - well, feel lazy. Actually reading her notes is something Monroe would do.

There was a loud crack from the Professor's wand. All the chatter in the class died down; all eyes focused on her.

"You have three specific enemies! Who for unknown reasons, are looking to do you harm! They are clever! They may strike at any time! Despite knowing this, you have to go on living life... and you have a thirst."

Tom sat up straighter. He was now quite glad he didn't read the notes, as this class was going to be one of the wonderful times that Merrythought went off book. She ought to do it more often, it actually makes her students think on rare occasion. Despite her hypothetical situations frequently being illogical, it was a nice break from reading on how to deal with boggarts.

She had paused to let the hypothetical situation take root in the class's imagination. "So! You decide you will go to the Three Broomsticks for a few drinks. No more than two, obviously you will not get drunk in your situation, but enough to take the edge off. After all, it's been a stressful day for you, and you need the drink and a social atmosphere... regardless of the dangers."

She looked around the classroom, her eyes magnified by her thick glasses. "How do you do this? How do you do this safely?"

Tom hesitated to raise his hand - to him, the lesson was a little foolish. You don't go out for any leisurely activities until you have slain your enemies! Unless you can combine the two, and make slaying your enemies a leisurely activity.

Merrythought wouldn't want to hear the simple, correct answer, however.

While Tom hesitated, she called on Cedric Bagshot to answer. "Yes Mr. Bagshot, go on then, tell me how you survive."

Idiot, this should be hilarious... Cedric took a moment to consider how to phrase his answer, and then simply said, "I'd pay the extra galleon to have the drinks delivered to my house, and let my home wards protect me."

There were a few murmurs of agreement around the room.

Tom wrinkled his nose. It was a halfway decent answer, assuming you had a fortress and took several other measures. But drinking something delivered by an unknown was nothing short of foolish. In fact, why on Merlin's green earth would you want to dull your senses in this sort of situation? Unless you're suicidal.

Professor Merrythought likewise poked holes in the boy's plan. "Even then, you would have to follow the delivery boy to be sure it wasn't an undercover reconnaissance mission."

The boy looked disappointed, when he should have been ashamed that he would have been killed. Cedric was a fool, and simply thought of this as a pointless game. It does seem slightly ridiculous, but the thought experiment could turn out incredibly important.

"Yes, Miss Black, you have a proposal?"

The dark-haired danger put a sweet edge into her voice and asked, "How long have my enemies been out to get me?" Tom almost snickered; anytime Bellatrix Black opened her mouth in Defense class, something outrageous was sure to come out. If only she didn't so patently obviously have a crush on him, he would have considered her for Battle Magic fights... Well, that, and she's more openly violent than I am. Around her fiance she was calmer, at least, but she was the most aggressive girl in the joint Ravenclaw and Slytherin class.

The Professor considered the question for a moment and replied, in a creepy voice, "One year, these enemies know you, very well indeed." Really now? Well, that changes my next idea...

"An entire year you say, and they know me?" Bellatrix Black put a funny confused look on her face. "If that's the case, I would have to assume I was being paranoid by this point."

Professor Merrythought stuttered, "Wh-what do you m-mean, of course you should be p-paranoid if-"

Black cut her off again with that deceptively innocent voice, "I meant that my enemies would have been dead within a month. Or I would have been. If for some reason, they were still getting to know me after a year, they would stay well away." She sniffed, "There are no enemies to be afraid of here, it's a trick question."

Most of the class laughed out of amusement at the "joke", but some stayed silent, for the same reason Tom and two others chuckled darkly.

She would likely draw them all into open battle at once, and kill herself, along with everyone within a square mile, with some wild unpredictable magic. The girl was arranged to marry Antonius Prewett, someone he could certainly manipulate, but he wondered if anyone could control Bellatrix Black.

Professor Merrythought frowned, "Hmm, is there anybody in this class who could survive this encounter?" And she and the whole class looked pointedly at Tom Riddle. "Mr. Riddle! Please explain to us how to stay alive in this scenario."

"Well, honestly Professor, if these enemies know me as well as you say, it would be as simple as doing something that they know I wouldn't do, more or less."

The Professor was frowning again.

"I mean, look. If they know me, and know I won't take any risks, which I wouldn't, then the obvious thing to do is go all out on a gamble." Tom thought for a moment and continued, "I walk into the bar, casual as you please, and have my drinks in peace. If they follow into the bar, they will either assume this person isn't myself, a distraction of some sort, and therefore flee, or they will assume that it is me. And, if they know me so well, they know I wouldn't just appear like that without some massive advantage ready to wield against them, and so, again they would flee."

"Mister Riddle, I don't think you can just make assumptions like that on how people will behave. You defeated the purpose of the lesson." The professor was shaking her head lightly. "You put yourself in incredible danger by bluffing like that."

Tom disagreed, "It wouldn't be a bluff, it would be a trap."

"How would you overtake them if they called your bluff, and fall into your 'trap'?"

"Magic." Tom replied simply. This response got a laugh from a few people for some reason, but the Professor was unimpressed.

Tom sighed, "Fine, then, another plan. You can never have enough plans in place." The professor smiled at that comment, and Tom went on. "Well before you left your temporary safe house, you check to make sure your spare wand is still secure in the hidden holster. Hmm, enchanting a device for temporary superhuman speed wouldn't be a bad idea either."

Tom paused to consider how else he'd prepare. "There a few other small devices I can think of which you may want to bring along as well, but I don't think I will mention them now."

The Professor tilted her head in curiosity at that, but before she could ask, Tom went on.

"You would then drink from one of your four Polyjuice vials, each of them containing a different appearance, nothing too obvious, but no-one overly ordinary either. That part may be tricky… Really, it would depend ultimately on whom you were trying to fool." Tom inhaled, then continued. "Then Disillusion yourself, and just for overkill, throw on an….. No, forget an invisibility cloak, not enough freedom of movement if you actually have to fight. Besides, if they already know who you are, and where you are, an invisibility cloak won't offer much concealment."

Professor Merrythought's grin grew even broader.

"From there, you Apparate to a random location, with no link to you. Then you can Apparate outside the bar. Then no one will know where you started. I know you can track a person, but I've never heard of a way to track where a person just Apparated from. But it's still possible…" He finished his thought almost as a question, as he stared into the air for a moment and tapped his cheek with his finger.

As expected the Professor chimed in, "Apparation tracking is quite advanced, and will only work in certain conditions, but even then it's quite difficult. I'll explain it a little to you after class, I'm sure you can work out the rest from there."

Tom allowed himself to show a smile; he was providing exactly the type of ridiculously over-complicated answer that she wanted to hear, and he would be rewarded with extra knowledge. Professor Merrythought often had little gems of lore she would dish out to Tom if he could but push the correct button. Fortunately, she mostly seemed under the impression Tom was but a curious student.

"The moment you arrived you would observe the scene closely, probably for an hour, at least, before you entered. Rather than cast detection charms, which might be noticed by a powerful opponent, you would have to feel around for magical resonance. Not as effective, of course, but it's better than the alternatives.

"Once you were sure that nobody else was in plain hiding, you could then very subtly slip the barmaid a pre-written note, in somebody else's hand, with your order, along with the exact amount of money. Do everything quickly and precisely, very subtle."

He was about to finish up but considered the situation further. "If for some reason after getting your drinks, you had to stay there to drink them, you wouldn't do it at the open bar! You would stay in the patio where there are fewer people to watch, plenty of escape options, and lots of room to fight if you have to.

"And no, I did not forget about raising shields, even invisible ones would be foolish. Any competent wizard would be able to detect the slight surge of defensive magic from an invisible corner. " Tom was now satisfied that if he followed that plan, and adapted to the situation as it played out, he could control the situation if it got out of hand.

Professor Merrythought apparently agreed. "Well thought, Tom. Normally I would expand, and ask the student how they planned to fight possibly three strong opponents at once if they had to, however you seem confident you would simply 'Find a way' to do it…"

Tom nodded, and Professor Merrythought shook her head.

"You are talented, Mister Riddle, but I think your ego is a little larger than it should be."

My ego is just the right size, thank you very much.

She turned to address the class. "I am afraid we don't have much time left, and we have material from the book to cover yet, quite a lot in fact, so I'll have to put off the practical lesson I had planned till the next class."

Tom had been looking forward to a real Defense class where they got to cast magic; perhaps he was doing too good a job at disrupting Merrythought's job. He sighed as she pulled out the textbook; as with all of their texts, this one was full of inaccuracies and covered irrelevant subjects. Without better textbooks, proper teachers were imperative. And this one is fading fast.

The Professor held the book open to show the class a picture, talking about how to deal with some type of giant spider that Tom had read about once. Rather than listen, he probed his memory for anything of importance. They hadn't seemed fearsome enough to really need to worry about - some magical strength, but no real intelligence. Not dangerous, to a trained wizard; perhaps a little girl might be in danger if she ran into one.

"The underbelly is vulnerable to curses, and with so many legs, a strong tripping Jinx will get them into perfect position for a hard Stunner to the soft flesh of the belly."

Back to the thought experiment, Tom decided that if you saw a giant spider and threw curses at it, the three others tracking you could come out and flank you, then overtake you.

"You aren't likely to encounter one any place except its home, in a forest, or cave system, which would likely be full of traps and hard terrain to fight on. "

And once you start to notice signs of their presence, you should simply apparate away. If you can't, forget the complex jinxes, there are two simple words that no magical protection can withstand, no matter where you strike it. Even if a person wasn't capable of that curse, or unwilling to use it at the time, they could simply use some type of overpowered brute force magic on it. Magical or no, it's still an insect, and it could be squashed.

Thinking of how flawed others' thinking was proved to be a great source of enjoyment to him.

Once I get this job, our first lesson will be Fiendfyre, so we can properly send these texts to the hell they belong in.

The professor continued to go on in detail about - something - for the next little while, and Tom observed his classmates. Besides the girls that tried to catch glances of him, almost all seemed absorbed and frightened while listening to the details; however, Tom noticed that Orego Burke was paying more attention to him then to class. Tom locked eyes with the boy for a few moments, he looked away, and that seemed to be the end of it.

Professor Merrythought closed the book and put it down. "The acromantula living deep in our own forbidden forest have been growing more restless and wild over the last few years, according to the gamekeeper." The professor made it sound like this was worrisome news. "He says he has never in his life seen them change their behavior patterns so drastically, it's as though they have been preparing for a storm, or some other large event, for at least the last four years. There has been talk of bringing in researchers to study this new pattern of behavior it seems significant. I suspect their change would make for an interesting Care Of Magical Creatures class."

Tom doubted that, who cared what the spiders were doing deep in the forest or why they were restless? I'm not taking Care of Magical Creatures, can we shut up about these things?

After class he waited until everybody left to approach The Professor in regards to their unfinished discussion.

"So tell me, Mister Riddle, who is it you are hoping to track from place to place?"

She was almost laughing, but there was a tinge of fear in her laughter. Tom was sure she wasn't completely sold on his innocence. He had to convince her he was simply eager to learn as much as possible for the sake of learning. It was the truth, but Tom could also see lots of other uses for tracking Apparation.

"It's not so much I expect I'll need to track anybody. I'm just curious how it would work exactly. You know, in case I ever need a drink while 3 enemies are out to get me," he joked back, hoping to put her at ease, then smiled his most charming smile. It apparently worked, because she waved him to a desk at the front of the class, and sat on top of her own to regard him.

"As you well know Tom, all magic leaves traces, and nearly all magic can be sensed, if a person is sensitive enough to that type of thing. That's the basic principal behind tracking a person who just Apparated... do you see what I am getting at?" She cocked her head at him.

Tom considered it. "I believe I do. I've also heard powerful magic rubs off on a person, and lingers after they are out of the area."

The Professor kept quiet and let Tom continue working it out.

"So, say, your house has heavy wards, or it contains some ancient device of power? After you Apparated out, the magical scent would linger on you? A person can trace that?" Tom was very curious now, this sounded like something he would be particularly good at: his sense of magical resonance was strong, he could feel even the smallest traces of lingering magic in the air or on an object.

Professor Merrythought nodded, "That's the essence of it, yes. I'm afraid I have to admit that I do not know how a person uses that to trace the original location. I have never been capable of it personally."

She seemed disappointed in that, Tom could understand. Failure to learn an exotic magic would be a hard pill to swallow.

With as much enthusiasm as he could muster, Tom replied, "Thank you, Professor, you have been very helpful. I always look forward to our chats."

Professor Merrythought smiled, "As do I, Tom, you really are a talented young man. I wouldn't be surprised if you ended up taking my job one day far down the road, once you get some real world experience. And realize your own limits, since you don't seem to believe they exist at the moment."

Tom let the insult wash over him, since she had no idea he was already destabilizing her reputation and planned to take her job far sooner than that. Maybe then I'll rub some salt in, but for now… He learned from his last failed plot that even if you can move quickly, usually it is better to play the long con.

He stepped out of the defense room, and nearly bumped into a girl, but he pivoted and spun out of the way, hand ready to summon his wand in an instant.

He dropped his guard slightly when he seen who it was.

"You should be more careful where you are going, Myrtle." How in Merlin's name does she just appear in front of me so often? Maybe Merrythought is wrong and tracking comes quite easily to some.

The awkward girl's eyes widened under her glasses. "Were… Were you about to curse me, Tom?"

Tom was still in a combat ready position.

"I still may." He said it only half-jokingly. The threatening undertone went completely over the dull girl's head and she laughed.

"Sorry, sorry, I did kind of come out of nowhere on you there, sorry about that!" She blushed and looked down as she continued, "I guess that's why you are so good in Defense class! Actually, that's what I wanted to talk to you about…"

Is she in my Defense class? I hadn't noticed. Not that Tom gave a toss about most girls. It would be one thing if they seemed to care about anything besides staring at him... He was adapted to it by now, but last year, when it began, he became uncomfortable enough to consider cursing off his nose.

The girl grew a deeper shade of red before she was able to speak again. "I was really impressed with how you answered the teacher's question! You really sound like you know how to take care of yourself!" she stammered, all in one breath, then finally looked up again. Even if he was interested in girls right now, this poor, foolish thing was certainly not somebody he would consider. Why she couldn't take a hint was a puzzle even he couldn't solve.

So he gave her another hint. He turned, started walking, and said just loudly enough to make sure she took it as a dismissal, "Yes, I take care of myself just fine."

"Bye Tom!" Myrtle gushed, as Tom's strides took him farther and farther from her.

And now, Black was approaching him. He sighed.

"You don't really like Myrtle, do you, Tom? I could see it." Black seemed proud of her obvious observation, and apparently jealous of Myrtle's conversation with Tom for some reason.

"As a matter of fact, I believe I am going to marry that girl, Bellatrix." Tom said it sarcastically, but the sarcasm either went over Black's head, or the comment was all she needed to go over the edge.

"She is an idiot." Black snapped as she watched Myrtle walk down the hall. Tom could feel the air growing cold around her. He had to settle this girl down before she did something stupid again.

"She is my idiot, and no worry of yours." Tom put some force into his voice to stop Black staring at Myrtle.

"As you say…" Black said, reluctantly, then continued, "A pity if some accident should - "

Tom cut her words off with a gesture from his wand.

"If I need something from you, I will tell you, Bella." He put an edge to the end of the sentence to make it clear this conversation had come to an end. Bellatrix Black turned and walked away without another word. The last thing I needed is Black cursing Myrtle into a thousand pieces in my name.

David Monroe seemed to embrace this problem; to him the attention of girls was a great joy and he went out of his way to encourage it. Tom on the other hand tried very hard to be curt with female students, but it only seemed to make some of them more interested.. Apparently his "mysterious and dangerous" aura had the unintended side effect of attracting certain types of females. At least with Black there was a chance of making her into a useful pawn at some point, a powerful witch without scruples could come in handy.

"Bellatrix Black, Abigail Myrtle…" He considered the uses he might be able to get from them as he walked.

Myrtle was malleable and weak willed, Tom was certain he could manipulate her into just about anything he needed with a few kind words. He was just as certain, alas, that her stupidity and weakness would cause problems if he tried to use her to any important end.

Black on the other hand…

If I asked her to prove that she could blow up The Three Broomsticks, I would be reading about a fiery massacre in tomorrow's paper, I expect she would stay to fight with the aurors who arrive as well. The girl had incredible book smarts and was in the top of all her classes, but her impulsive decisions called her intelligence into question. He almost felt sorry for Antonius Prewett, saddled to marry her...

The fact was, like most girls, Black would do almost anything for Tom without hesitation, and she was powerful enough to use as a brute force "sledge hammer" if he needed an expendable one, but her willfulness and unpredictability was a weakness that would bring Tom down if he made use of her without a substantial amount of training.

Tom thought about Myrtle and Black as he walked.

If nothing else they could be useful scapegoats, witnesses, or sacrifices...

Bellatrix Black stalked off down the hallway, feeling slightly angry.

"The only reason I let him get away with talking to me like that is because he is the only guy here who can back up his words." Her fiance, Antonius Prewett, certainly couldn't. Every year she'd had to remind him: they were betrothed from birth, simply so their parents could be happy with a pureblood marriage after they graduated. As long as he did whatever she wanted, she would pretend to agree with him in public. Unless, of course, he tried to touch her, in which case she would demonstrate exactly why she had higher marks in every class than he did. And when he begged to be allowed to ask Dorea Potter to Hogsmeade last year, she almost cursed him, till she realized that would be the perfect cover for her crush on Riddle.

Riddle, who definitely did not have lower marks than she did in every class. True, sometimes Black grew so angry with how Tom disregarded her that it made her want to curse him. Bloody fool might even like it. It probably wasn't worth the risk of finding out though. She was quite sure Tom did like her, but in his own strange way. The challenge of getting him to admit it was exciting to her.

She tried to imagine Tom Riddle coming to her door at 8pm with a rose in hand and sweet words on his tongue. It was a hilarious image. When her fiance, had done something similar, it had been hilarious in a totally different way...

Well. Tom Riddle with a rose would never happen, but she was optimistic something else could happen.

Tom was probably the only 5th year who could actually out-match her with magic. His views more or less lined up with her own - rather than reporting her to the Ministry of Magic for suggesting a ritual to sacrifice a herd of unicorns for immortality, he had cast a number of charms to ensure they weren't overheard - and he seemed deeply interested her opinions.

He does call me Bella, after all. Just like Father used to, Black thought with affection.

"Hey Bellatrix!" Mandy Perkins called. She turned around to see Mandy smiling at her."I liked that joke you made in class about your enemies, they better not mess with you, hey?"

Black tried to recall making a joke, but she didn't have a habit of trying to make people laugh. "The only joke is that somebody would purposely want to be my enemy. Do you want to be my enemy?" Bellatrix asked Mandy the question as if she were asking the girl to have a butterbeer.

Mandy looked taken aback. "Of course not! I was just trying to be friendly is all, Merlin's pants!"

The girl walked off muttering something, Black was sure she heard the words "hopeless" and "lunatic" under the girl's breath.

Chapter 4: Tom Riddle and Higher Learning

note: again, changes to canon are intentional.

Chapter Four – Tom Riddle and Higher Learning

Tom had verified that he still had nearly two hours before his scheduled lesson, but it was a long and complex journey to get to this, the one class that mattered more than all others.

The hour made him consider Disillusionment, but he didn't dare while Dumbledore was on the grounds. This way, he could easily explain his wanderings as a night walk by the lake; if he chose to break curfew, nobody would say otherwise. Whereas if Dumbledore saw that he was clearly hiding himself, the old man would figure something was up. These excursions are the last thing the old man needs to be aware of.

Instead, Tom constantly let his magic flow outwards - around corners and into rooms - to check for any resonances that would indicate a human, elf or ghost. With his path clear the entire way to the front doors, he exited the school and made his way across the dark grounds.

It was in his second year that his attention had settled on the anomaly of the Shrieking Shack.

The stories he heard and read about simply made no sense. The type of "ghost" who simply wanted to break things, make noise, and scare people wouldn't stay in an abandoned shack.

Besides, if it was locked up, how would anyone even know?

Perhaps once there was a ghost, but it should have moved on when people stopped living there. As a matter of fact, the building itself should have been demolished if the haunting was truly that dangerous. And if it wasn't that dangerous, if it was an appropriate "tourist attraction," why was it completely locked up?

As far as Tom could discern, maybe one out of fifty people who visited Hogsmeade took a look at the Shack, and when nothing at all happened, they decided not to waste time there again, and occasionally spread the word of the fraud. There were a few "lucky" ones that were scared away by some simple banging and laughter from inside on occasion. But Tom had heard a seventh-year Gryffindor known for being a founding member of the "Prank Squad," boasting about scaring off tourists more than once. The group could certainly be a sufficient explanation for the odd, infrequent "ghostly" encounters.

It had to have another purpose. Tom realized that the remote location in the village and the positioning of it in relation to Hogwarts could be relevant, if it contained an exit to one of the many secret tunnels from the school grounds.

Unfortunately, not a single one of the passages he could find were long enough to reach the Shack, and after a few weeks of exploring, he was ready to write off this theory.

But then, something else caught his curiosity. Walking past the Whomping Willow, he realized what an odd feature it was. A tree that knocked any student who came near into the hospital wing, what idiotic headmaster had thought that was a good idea?

Unless it was guarding something.

It was easy enough to find the privacy to cast at it, since no student was so foolhardy as to come near it, but none of his spells seemed to have any effect. Until he cast an orange bolt that struck a large knot near the bottom, making the tree freeze, and some of the roots retracted to reveal a small hole. Tom returned to investigate it after dark, and ended up exactly where he thought he might. That was his first time truly breaking out of school and into the wizarding world. He discovered many amazing things afterhours, but it took a year for his most valuable discovery.

One night spent creeping around Hogsmeade, Tom happened across two wizards arguing heatedly in an alley, words about to turn to wands. Curious to see a real duel, Tom took cover, and watched from under his "borrowed" invisibility cloak.

When the wands did come out, Tom was rather disappointed. He hoped to see some high-level curses flying, perhaps even some blood. Instead, the large, bald man drew his wand faster than the eye could catch, slamming the other man into a wall so hard it would have shattered, if the buildings here weren't warded against stray curses from frequent midnight duels.

His opponent down, the man slowly turned towards where Tom had ducked behind a similarly warded waste bin.

"I see you there!" The man said harshly, "Just throw off the cloak, and try to do what you mean to do. I'll re-holster my wand to give you a fair shot then."

Tom was caught; this man was clearly powerful enough that Tom couldn't overtake him with his best efforts. He had an idea, though, and he threw down his cloak and stood up. "I mean to try and convince you to teach me to fight."

Upon seeing Tom, the man laughed, "Go back to bed, boy," and turned to walk away. Tom was intent, now; he drew his wand, pulled down hard, and an inky black jet started sizzling towards the man. It winked out on an invisible shield a foot away from the man. The large man stopped in his tracks, and turned to Tom.

"You tickled me," he said in an awed tone. He studied Tom for a few moments: his stance, the way he held his wand, the magic radiating off of him, probably a number of other things as well. He nodded his head, apparently in approval.

"I'll tell you what, boy." (Tom really hated that word.) "Keep coming around. I don't hide myself under any invisibility cloak, Tobo Mott's easy to find." The large man left it at that.

Tom was unsure of the implication. "And once I find you again?"

He snorted. "How about, you try to get the drop on me. If you can't do that, I can't expect you to be worth my time. I'll give you three, no four, tries to impress me." His voice seemed to indicate that he expected failure. "I know you're one of Dippet's, so I won't truly hurt you. You'll see just how little you know, boy."

The man turned and walked away without another word. Odd, but he was certainly a powerful fighter, and Tom intensely desired to be taught by a powerful fighter. At least these four attempts will be fun.

The first two tries had ended with sufficient disaster to convince Tom that this man was indeed somebody he wanted to learn from.

The first time, Tom had tried ambushing him with an all-out attack high up on broomstick. Tobo had simply kept walking straight towards the rainbow jet as it rushed towards him. Just before Tom thought he would succeed, Tobo had yelled something incomprehensible, and his spell rushed back at him, thrice as strong as before. Without the power or time to avoid it, Tom was knocked him off his broom, rushing twenty feet sideways, before he began his exceedingly painful fall.

The second time, Tom had invited Bellatrix to Hogsmeade, hoping that she would bring Tobo's guard down.

And the consequences for that, I still pay for.

But on his third attempt, he was able to take the man unaware.

It was in the same alley they had first met. Tom Riddle approached the man with open hands and said "Good evening."

The large man smiled, and replied, "Hello, whoever you are." Tom didn't even see him pull his wand before the man spat, "Polyfluis Reverso!" The spell transformed Tom Riddle back into a confused old man who was just starting to realize he wasn't Tom Riddle.

Which was just as he had planned.

From inside his Conjured waste bin, Tom muttered an incantation, and the sound of rapid footsteps seemed to approach the man from behind.

He then immediately Banished the bin and stepped forward, mere feet from the man, just as he turned his back.

Tom bellowed the incantation to one of the strongest shield breakers he had read about. A bluff: that spell was out of his league at the time. But the man bought it, dropping his initial shields to put up a much stronger one, to withstand the breaker.

Instead, what came was a long wooden shaft Tom had Transfigured. Physical objects would pass through that particular shield, while magic couldn't. The shaft struck the man clean in the ribs, and Tom was surprised to see him actually recoil slightly.

"Technically, that could have just as easily been a sword, and I would have nearly cut you in half," Tom said smugly. The man was staring at the pole in disbelief. Tom cancelled the Transfiguration and threw the branch aside. "I think I've proven my competence to survive your training."

After casting a Healing Charm, he looked Tom over. "Aye, you're certainly sneaky enough to dodge death itself, I would imagine." He put out his hand and they shook, quite firmly. "Call me Tobo Mott."

"First lesson…" The punch came at the same time the sentence did. Tom knew how to fight - he had been bullied enough back in London to learn - but the man had him in his grasp. The fist connected with Tom's head and sent him sprawling, dazed, and angry. He rolled as he fell and managed to land on his knees; he sprung up in a rage and drew his wand up, spitting the nastiest Hex he knew.

Nothing happened. A quick glance at his hand showed it empty; a quick glance at Tobo showed him holding it.

"Still not sneaky enough, but you might do for now." Smiling, Tobo tossed Tom his wand back. "If you plan to fly off the handle and try to murder me every time I best you, boy, this isn't going to work. There are lessons in loss, which you miss completely by getting angry."

"The lesson I missed was that you aren't trustworthy," Tom hissed.

"Most people would say that, aye. I especially won't be when it comes to your lessons. Fights aren't fair, and I won't be either."

Despite himself, Tom couldn't help smiling. Fairness never seemed natural to me anyway.

"In exchange for personal lessons, I will ask you to do a small job for me once and a while." Tobo studied Tom, waiting for a reaction, but Tom didn't give him one. "Nothing truly dangerous, just a little help here and there with a plot."

Still controlling his anger, he replied, "Fine, then." As long as this man understands that I expect absolutely everything he can give me, and I expect he can give me quite a lot. Tom normally had others do his bidding; it was not pleasant to be on the other end.

"You're clever, and sneaky. I have a feeling you don't have a particular sense of duty to uphold the law either. That, I can use, more than any type of gold payment for my time and effort." Tobo's face was now blank.

And so it had been for the last several years. Tom would steal an artifact from somebody, act as a spy, or even send a message to somebody who had wronged Tobo in one of his many business ventures.

Tom didn't use violence to send the messages; Tobo wanted him to be clever about it, and subtle enough to not send either of them to Azkaban.

Tom always made sure to perform as expected, or better. In exchange, he received extensive training from the powerful, dangerous and mysterious man, Tobo Mott. He was even taught powerful spells he wasn't likely to find in the Hogwarts library, or learn in class.

Tobo's training over the years had helped make Tom powerful. In fifth year, certainly, he outclassed everybody. Only two other students in Hogwarts made Tom wary these days, Bellatrix Black and Thomas Chang.

It had been a long walk through the tunnel and out of the shack, past the Hogwarts wards where he could apparate to Tobo's well-warded quarters. As he swiped his wand just to the edge of the ward, it glowed, meaning it was safe to pass through. He entered the small entrance room, but could go no further until Tobo came to unlock the wards. As usual, he came at the appointed time, and the barrier dissolved as he approached. Tom walked into the living room to discuss today's lesson.

Tobo looked particularly grave, making Tom feel uneasy. "Listen, Tom".

He normally doesn't call me by my name, this can't be good...

"There's no lesson tonight, a shame you wasted your night by walking out here, but I couldn't send an owl without heavy code to explain. "

Because the code itself would have revealed there was some plot afoot... "Why is there no lesson tonight, Tobo? You aren't telling me something." He briefly tried to bypass the man's Occlumency shield, but it was yet too powerful. So he waited for an answer.

"I've got troubles, kid." Tobo looked the most sincere he'd ever seen him.

Now this I may be able to exploit. "You will need to elaborate if you expect me to solve your problem for you."

Tobo laughed at that, a legitimate belly-laugh, something else Tom had never seen before.

"Kid, if I can't solve this, you can't either. You're out of your league, these are adult games."

Tom had considered himself an adult for years. He stood up straighter and looked Tobo in the eyes. "Please, could you explain all the relevant details to me? If I succeed where you have failed, give me a blank cheque to ask of you anything."

Tobo rolled his eyes at the request, but he sighed and started to explain how a certain man, a competitor, had acquired documents and other unknown evidence of one of Tobo's main operations. This man had agreed to keep this evidence sealed as long as Tobo went out of business and shared his most valued trade secrets.

"Now, I can't dare enchant another device for somebody, and I'd rather die before being blackmailed… Even if I could trust that he won't have me sent to Azkaban anyways." Tobo was looking very tired. "I don't think you realize the kind of money there is in that type of specialty work, Kid."

And here I thought it was your main source of income, Tom thought dryly.

Tobo went on; the man was apparently well protected, armed with an ancient device unknown to Tobo but apparently held great shielding power.

"He neither raises shields of his own nor tries to dodge attacks; I couldn't understand it during our brief encounter. Even comparing some of the most arcane magic I know, which has a similar effect to his hidden device, did nothing to reveal its true nature to me. He fled when I once cast the Killing Curse, but that seems to be his only weakness."

Unless it's a bluff... but I doubt any device or spell could resist the green death. "Is he otherwise powerful?" Tom wondered if this could be an even match for him.

"Not particularly, but more than you are. Not a third the fighter you are though…" The man seemed to be picturing Tom facing off against the opponent for a moment before he shook his head.

Tom kept pressing for information. "Where does he reside?" Normally, Tobo was powerful enough to simply assault nearly any compound and destroy everything.

"That's the thing; it's some very special magic…" Tobo frowned in confusion. "His home is small, deep in the forest, and it moves."

Confused himself, Tom repeated, "It moves? What do you mean it moves?"

"I mean, if a person approaches it, it will vanish as if you were a Muggle looking on a highly warded building. From all I can tell it literally changes location rather than anything else. It does the same if any powerful magic approaches."

Tom considered this. A plan was beginning to take shape. "How else is it warded?"

"Sufficiently, I would expect. But then, with this unfindable home, I doubt he would go through the same amount of troubles that I do."

"So it's probably not warded very well because of the high magic being used to 'relocate' it when it's triggered, correct? Do you think he would even bother to have an anti-Apparition ward on it? Since nobody could actually Apparate in without knowing where it is…"

"I don't know, and it doesn't matter. As you said, no way to know where it is."

Tom wasn't so sure about that. "Can we lure him out of his home, just for a brief encounter even? We do not have to do anything aside from meet him in person."

Tobo shook his head. "I'm not stupid boy, of course I tried to track where he Apparated from, but there were no tells from all I could sense. And trust me when I say, I can sense a great deal more than you."

They discussed for a while the particulars of this man and what he was known for.

Finally Tom thought he had a workable plan. He asked, "Suppose I get to him, what would you have me do?"

Tobo smiled at the question, as if a child asked why water was wet. "Try not to get killed."

"I don't intend to die, ever." Tom replied, it was a bold statement but he knew his justifications.

Tobo looked Tom over with pity. "Hmm, I don't think any of us intend to, life just likes to kill us, is all."

"If I find a way to get to him, what would you have me do?" he repeated.

Tobo sighed, "In an ideal world, you would destroy any evidence he has on me, and kill him, hopefully without making the front page of the newspaper again."

Note to self, do not involve Bellatrix.

Well. Tom had no problems with the idea of killing this man. The first person to die at my hand, but somebody has to be first. It seemed highly unlikely that Tom would never have a good reason to kill someone, so it only seemed logical to start practicing early.

However… He felt certain that he could go above and beyond to truly impress his mentor.

They discussed the situation for a while longer, in particular the specifics of the powerful device the man had at his disposal. Tobo had no recollection of any lore about such a device; however, Tom felt an itch in the back of his mind, when Tobo had said that the device seemed to absorb magic, rather than actually block it.

But there's no need for Tobo to ever know what the device is if I end up with it.

Tom decided it was time to wrap up this discussion; he needed to get back to the castle. And I must make another stop.

"What type of time frame am I looking at here, Tobo?"

"The sooner the better Kid, I'm losing money and customers." Tobo perked up with an idea, "Tell you what, if you do pull this off, I'll give you the entire profits from my first order back in business."

Tom waved the offer off. "I can acquire my own gold if I need it. What I need from you is… Magic."

Tobo nodded gravely, unhappy with an open request. "If you ask for something too advanced, you know I can't teach you, even if you can help me. Some seals can only be opened by one's own self."

Tom was frustrated; from what he understood of the Interdict of Merlin, Tobo could teach him anything he knew if he truly willed it. It's a matter of him wanting to teach, not a matter of being able to. "The spell I seek is hardly uncommon. In fact, I think it's a perfectly suitable spell to teach somebody to see if they are capable of wielding powerful forces."

As realization dawned, Tobo looked almost. "Kid, you don't just test powerful magic, either you control it, or it consumes you. And possibly many others."

"I have no fear of being consumed, and the only people who need fear being consumed by me are those I have decided to destroy." Tom realized that sounded too arrogant. He had to try to convince Tobo he understood the implications here, so he toned it down. "I've read about Magical Italy, I've heard rumors of the fall of Atlantis, I am aware of the Wind Weavers of legend. I have no intention of playing with magic out of my league."

Tobo had a blank face. "Aye, you do deserve a little credit, I suppose." He looked at Tom for a lingering moment, and then sighed. "I agree to your terms, Tom Riddle. Rid me of this problem, and I will grant you the knowledge."

Tom smiled; he could almost smell the unholy burning of Fiendfyre already.

With such a short time before sunrise, Tom decided to use his old fallback, "I was reading and lost track of time," to explain his absence from breakfast.

He reached the odd shop at the end of the twisting road, where, if you had the gold, the owner sold Muggle antiques, knick-knacks and curios - and whatever else you could find in the basement. Their lacks of regular hours were another benefit Tom often took advantage of.

Old wrinkled Groleo answered the door, looking for all the world like a harmless elderly fellow. His shop wasn't warded in any way, and he never had a shield up - or a care in the world.

Who needs wards when you have all the lore from those scrolls? Tom wished he could take the whole shop for his own.

But needs must; Tom struggled with a heavy bag of gold from his robes, handed it to the old man without a word, and was ushered in. Groleo led Tom to a random side shelf full of what Tom thought resembled Muggle "snow globes". Slowly, Groleo lifted his trembling, claw-like hand. A smear of black now stood where the shelf had been, and into this abyss Tom strode.

He now stood in the large dusty basement, with no sign of the rest of the shop. At least, I've always assumed it was a basement, but who knows, with Groleo? A shame he won't actually tell anyone his secrets, of all people he'd know something about the magic required to move a house…

There were shelves lining the walls, full of large tomes, ancient scrolls and Pensieves. There were no candles, yet the room was visible, barely lit enough to read in. The overall effect makes this room seem extra-secretive and foreboding.

Thanks to the Interdict, a lot of the information here was useless, incomprehensible gibberish until one had learned the seeds of those spells and rituals. More valuable to him were the texts that went into detail on very interesting things, devices of power being one of the many intriguing subjects.

Tom never had as much time or money to spend in this place as he would have liked, so he had some trouble finding the book he remembered referencing the Amulet of Asshia. Fortunately - ha! - it had not been sold, and he found the passage:

"The Amulet has been known to exist for at least 700 years. Although its actual origins are obscured by legend and fantasy, it is reasonable to assume that, due to its properties and approximate age, the crafter was Ronell Manailur himself."

I've seen that name before. If he were an artificer, that would explain why Manailur's name pops up around so many magical mysteries.

"The Amulet appears as two parts: a golden chain, with links that extend and retract to fit around the user. The chain itself has also been known to retract to the point that it strangles the life from the user. There is no extant evidence why it has betrayed owners, but it is worth noting that the one confirmed death via strangulation was none other than 'Percius Makier', a distant relation of one of Manailur's enemies while he lived."

Tom decided to very carefully research his heritage before trying to use this device himself.

"Secondly, the chain suspends a large blue gem of magical creation. This gem is noted for seemingly drawing the magic out of nearly any attack, rather than trying to deflect or block the incoming magic. Once the Amulet is securely around the wearer's throat, the gem binds itself to the person's body and makes them almost impervious to attack. The exact limitations of its power are unknown, except that it has been seen to stop even the power of ghphbjhhjqpxr.

"It should be noted that the device has a trade-off: in exchange for utter protection, a wizard's own power will be fettered and slower under the influence of the amulet."

And that was that; the Amulet didn't do anything else. But that was enough. That would be a fine thing to own indeed.

As always, the shop tempted Tom to stay here the rest of the day, soaking up any knowledge he could, and simply come up with an explanation for his absence at school.

Sighing, Tom closed the book and reverently set it down on the table. The book gently floated up and back into its position on the shelf.

That's definitely something to steal for my own Dark lair's bookshelves.

Finally, Tom stood up and walked straight towards the exit: a space between two shelves. He found himself stepping out the front door of the shop. All that magic for books, yet a customer has to actually shut the front door. Groleo is insane.

On his way back, he wondered if he shouldn't ask Bellatrix a few questions. I can't tell her anything, but her store of facts about obscure dark magic from the past has surprised me before.

Aside from that, he could easily move on to phase one of his plan. He would need to find three true-forged rings, and more importantly, quit hesitating and get on with practicing the extremely advanced technique he had been mentally building for the last year.

Chapter 5: Tom Riddle and Saturday

Author's note: Just a reminder that things that look like canon misfires are on purpose.

Chapter Five – Tom Riddle and Saturday

A normal wizard might, after having spent his night discussing a seemingly intractable problem, reading more information, and walking for miles - a normal wizard might want to catch up on his sleep.

The way to eat an elephant is one bite at a time. Tom Riddle currently sat at his desk with a fresh sheet of parchment and outlined the broad steps of his plan. Things always seemed simpler if you broke them down that way.

"Step One: Locate and penetrate a small shack hidden by uncertain arcane magic in a vast forest."

Tom saw no reason to be concerned yet.

"Step Two: Overwhelm Dark Wizard who cannot be touched by most of my magic."

Tom could think of several quite simple other ways to incapacitate a person. Moving forward.

"Step Three: Steal the device of power, find out how to wield it without being trapped by unknown magic."

If Bellatrix didn't know something relevant, Tom could always set the amulet aside for further investigation.

"Step Four: Deliver the Dark Wizard to Tobo for questioning."

That was more than Tobo had asked for - and that was the way Tom liked to operate.

There. Shouldn't take but a couple of days.

Having settled that, he cast an Encryption Charm on the paper, then put it with his History of Magic notes. While normally, he preferred to sneak out to the library unseen, Bellatrix was usually up early as well, and he wanted to see if she could help him at all with the Amulet.

Today, however, something caught his attention in the common room, so he summoned a book from within his robes and it appeared in hand as though it had always been there. Tom sat down and pretended to read it in his usual seat.

Instead of having finished hours ago, one of the House Elves remained working in the common room. Probably because of the fourth-year girl trying to speak with it, literally begging it to respond to her.

"Orney! Pleeeeaaase! You know me, Ashley! Please, stop ignoring me! Why won't you talk to me? We - we used to talk for hours while you cleaned my bedroom..." The girl was sobbing now.

Tom bit his lip to stop from smirking. What do you know, the old fool predicted it perfectly. Tom surely never would have thought about the consequences to sentimental idiots banned from all house elf interaction. But then, why hadn't he thought to just make the elves invisible in the first place, if he didn't want such pathetic results? The man has some foresight, but obviously not enough.

"Please, Orney! Just, please, just say goodbye, I know, I know it's against the rules, but please just - please, just one last word!" Ashley was absolutely wailing, loudly enough that people were starting to come out to see what the commotion was. The Elf finally turned to look at Ashley, tears in its eyes as well, to Ashley's shock and silence.

"Goodbye, Ashley." The elf gasped then wailed as it ran from the room; the girl fell to the floor, crying anew, while about an audience of around fifteen students gathered in disbelief.

The Elf will be going off to hurt itself, very badly for disobeying a direct command like that. Dumbledore had to have stressed to the elves not to say a single word to any student, to prevent another similar plot by me or anyone else. Apparently this Ashley girl would rather have the Elf punish itself than... not say Goodbye? And then never speak to it again?

This was all too bizarre for Tom to try to puzzle out; he looked at the crying girl in confusion one last time and walked out of the common room. He didn't like feeling confused, and he was beginning to grow angry at himself for wanting to solve a puzzle not worth his time. Perhaps breakfast and a pretense of socializing would calm him down. It wouldn't hurt to actually be seen around school a couple of times this weekend either.

"What's up with MacNair lately?" Terence Keen asked the Slytherin table as Tom took his usual seat.

A tall blonde girl replied, "Likely upset about his House Elf not speaking with him anymore."

Tom burst out, "What?" That doesn't sound right…

The girl looked at Tom and said, "It was his family's Elf, it came to Hogwarts with him, Walden knew it since he was a baby. And now that it's a Hogwarts employee, they can't even speak anymore. He was so angry he tried to curse the poor thing's head right off. Luckily the Elves are warded against students' spells, but of course it had to be reassigned."

Tom was well aware of the warding, otherwise he might have used something besides trickery and loopholes in his plot. But he was quite surprised at MacNair's depth of feeling. I may have to reassess his usefulness.

"Well, where is he now?"

The blonde girl just shrugged and continued to eat.

"So Tom, what are your plans for today?" Tom slowly turned right and stared at Thomas Chang.

Chang originally came from China; they receive their wands at age six there, and train extensively in combat. Tom had traded some help with homework and other things like that for some of Chang's exotic spells. The boy knew magic Tom had never even heard of. Nothing truly impressive - he was still young - but there were some useful tricks the Chinese had come up with.

"I have some researching to do, and then I am going to practice Transfiguration for a few hours."

"Why would you practice schoolwork on a Saturday?" Chang asked Tom jokingly.

"Why would I need to practice my school work at all?" Tom replied completely seriously. "I have my own research to do, speaking of which I should get to it." Enough socializing. I don't have the time to try to relate to these people.

On his way to the library, he reflected on Chang a bit. Perhaps I am overestimating him, he seems to have lost the passion for learning he had when he first came to Britain. Disappointing.

This morning seemed to be full of one letdown after another. Everyone is just so weak. Hm. Maybe I could tell Bellatrix that Chang has been insulting her, and then we can see what he can really do.

Although it was an idle thought, he felt a bit of a shiver as he considered, honestly, if he could introduce Bellatrix Black to Thomas Chang in the context of Battle Magic.

I can just see the Forbidden Forest, completely on fire, with the heat from the purple flames starting to melt the school off in the distance as though it were made of wax.

On second thought, perhaps that should wait for Tom to become immortal - or at least fireproof.

Bellatrix wasn't immediately available when he entered the library; all things considered, that was probably the worse option when he saw who was at a table near the entrance, surrounded by Hufflepuffs.

"Oh, hello there Tom, how are you today?" Why he thinks trying to push my buttons is a good idea is beyond me.

"I'm fine, Monroe. Are those friends I see there?"

All the Duffers were girls, naturally. "Yeah, I make a lot of friends." Monroe was actually grinning.

Tom smirked and replied, "I'm sure you find it easy. You could pull a Knut out from a girl's ear, and they'll think you Merlin reborn." Two of them gave him hostile looks, while the others were just confused.

Monroe apparently finally remembered he was a Slytherin, started to look ashamed at cozying up with some Hufflepuff girls. But his face relaxed, he pushed his chair back, told the girls to wait a moment, then walked over to the roped off area delineating the Restricted section.

Giving Tom a smug look, he walked past it and picked a book off the shelf, thumbing through it casually while leaning against the shelf. Only his mouth smiled as he said, "Say what you like Tom, it doesn't bother me. I can do this and you can't."

Tom was careful to keep his anger hidden. "Except that I could bypass the wards if I needed, I don't need permission like you." Well. I probably could get past the wards; the problem is that Dumbledore would certainly know about it if I did.

Tom had never been given permission to enter the warded section, not even once. He had asked three teachers with innocent enough excuses, but they all either fully explained to him what he was asking permission to learn about, or they sent him to a teacher who could. Who but Dumbledore would have warned the staff? Surely he must realize I actually need access at some point, or I wouldn't be able to become a Professor...

The memory of Groleo's shop calmed him down. Hogwarts certainly doesn't have a monthly subscription to magazines that contain articles titled "1001 Ways To Make Corpses."

"As much as I love our intellectual discourse, I do have business elsewhere. A pleasure as always, Mr. Monroe."

With an insolent bow, Monroe returned to his table. The sight of his back made Tom draw his wand, but he turned and walked away before Monroe saw. One day I'm going to Transfigure that whelp into a glass vase and cast Reducto to see how he likes being in a thousand pieces.

Fortunately for Monroe, Bellatrix wasn't in the library, so Tom was able to leave before his fury grew.

All right. If I were Bellatrix Black, where would I be?

The girl liked to spend her free time wandering the halls. This had not been a mystery Tom could solve by following her around invisibly, except that she seemed to want to avoid her fiancé. Tom had quietly mentioned this to her, one day when they were hiding out together, and she blurted out, "I'm afraid I might kill him right here in school."

Tom had nearly shuddered at that; she had been completely serious. And of course if she does anything at all, I'll get blamed for it.

So now he tried a path he'd found her on before, through a corridor in the dungeons, when he heard somebody step out of the classroom behind him.

"What are you doing now, Mister Riddle? I dislike the way you stalk through my hallway; it makes me want to reach for a bezoar, just in case." Professor Slughorn was chuckling and looking up and down the hallway, to make sure they were alone - or to make sure they weren't.

A pity Bezoars don't work on Transfiguration sickness. "Have no fear sir; I'm occupied with figuring out how to bring down a different Dark Wizard at the moment," Tom joked along.

"Hah! Dark Wizard, you give me too much credit Tom. I'd never survive as a Dark Wizard."

I agree completely.

"Surely you've considered poisoning him? Personally that's the way I would do it if I had to." Professor Slughorn liked to make dark jokes, but Tom could tell his heart wasn't into it. More than likely, it's just to get on my good side.

"Yes, I suppose poisoning does make the most sense, thank you Professor."

Slughorn chuckled again, "Ah I feel safer already knowing that the world will soon be less one Dark Wizard."

Tom smirked. "Well, if they'd just make me Defense Professor already, the world wouldn't fear Dark Wizards."

The next laugh was a bit forced. "All jokes aside, Mister Riddle, you are only in your fifth year and have yet to even take your OWLs. You know I can't make any suggestions or recommendations for you."

I had forgotten about those bloody stupid tests. Tom sighed. "Yes, well, in any case, sir, I have to prepare to assault the enemy's home. So I'll leave you to it."

Professor Slughorn was smiling freely again. "Ah, good luck to you Tom, I'm sure you will make Salazar Slytherin himself proud." Slughorn saluted Tom, and Tom returned it before walking away.

Almost another hour was spent blithering around Hogwarts before Tom saw Bellatrix, outside by the lake, sitting halfway up a tree.

Tom looked up the tree. "Come down from there." He didn't want her looking down on him as they spoke.

"I like the view, the clouds' reflection on the lake is so pretty."

"Bella. Come down."

Bellatrix sighed and gently floated down from the tree.

Tom began warding the area so they could talk in private. Unfortunately, Bellatrix always grew far too excited when he did this.

He could tell she was only waiting for him to finish the privacy enchantments to speak, so as soon as he finished but before replacing his wand, he said, "Bella, tell me all you know of defensive artifacts."

"Oh." Bellatrix frowned. "Generally, they are made from things that already have certain properties. I don't think they are often made from scratch, but rather have shields built into them, and folded over and over on themselves, like forging a sword."

Tom shook his head. "No, I don't mean a device for blocking attacks; I mean something that totally renders them inert."

Bellatrix's eyes grew wide. "But I've never heard of anything like that before! That would be seriously powerful. Are you talking about something specific?"

Tom already had his cover story. "Yes, but I plan to craft it myself, eventually. But what types of other protections would one put on such a device once they worked out the fundamentals? Say I made an amulet to wear around the throat, surely it should strangle anybody who happened to defeat me in some way…" Tom tapped his cheek with his finger, finally allowing the girl to speak.

"No, I mean... you could but… Most of these devices tend to have a mind of their own, they will betray their master if legitimately defeated. I don't know why, but my father told me that's almost always the way it works in legends, the powerful devices want to go to powerful wizards."

So I just have to defeat the wielder of the amulet? If the device simply handed itself over this would be much simpler, but he didn't trust that it would be that simple.

Tom waved his wand, and the world washed in around them again.

"Is that all?" Bellatrix sounded disappointed.

"No, you can also go find Aerys Flintwood, and have him come to my dorm immediately. In fact, tell him to join you in my dorm, tell him there is gold involved, so binding him and dragging him along won't be necessary this time, Bellatrix."

Bellatrix looked intrigued, "What is this -"

"Now, if you will…" Tom gestured back towards the school and Bellatrix set off on her errand.

As Tom sat at his desk waiting, he practiced a few drills. He gestured with his wand and a glowing bat appeared, then lowered his wand and closed his eyes for a few moments to allow the bat to fly around. He snapped his eyes open and shot a small jet of blue light shot out, sending both back to non-existence.

Tom was about to conjure another bat when he felt somebody reaching for his door through his wards. Releasing the wards, the door opened just as Bellatrix was about to knock.

She was standing there with the short weasel-faced boy.

"Thank you Bellatrix, you may wait outside." Tom said as he gestured Flintwood into his dorm, and shut the door on Bellatrix.

"Bellatrix said you had some kind of job for me, Riddle?" The boy said warily. Tom found that out strange, as the boy was usually rather happy to earn some money.

"What else did she say?" Tom could feel his magic leak with annoyance; likely the boy felt it too.

"She… She said that if I didn't report to your dorm within 10 minutes flat you would give me a 10 minute head start to flee Hogwarts before you set after me."

Damn you, Black! "No, no, no…" Tom took a breath and composed himself again.

"Look, Flintwood… All right. Look. Twenty-five galleons. How long to acquire three rings of specific metals?"

Flintwood straightened up and smiled. "I imagine I could find them somewhere within a couple of hours."

"Tin, Iron and Platinum, please deliver to Bellatrix." He waved the door open again. "Well, I wouldn't want to keep you."

Flintwood looked a little confused, but left without any questions.

Alchemy provided some valuable secrets, especially as most wizards didn't give the subject a second thought once they heard it was all about "turning metal to gold." Few realized there was magic in metal, not much, but enough for some small advantage.

Tom saw Bellatrix still standing outside his room. "Bella, I will need you to guard the door for me. If anybody other than the headmaster himself comes to interrupt me I want you to…" He thought twice about saying "curse them into oblivion," as this was Bellatrix Black.

"That is. If anybody comes to interrupt me, tell them I am studying in the library. Then take them there as if you were looking for me in the first place. I cannot be interrupted for the next few hours."

Bellatrix tilted her head in confusion but simply nodded, and Tom closed the door on her again.

Tom prepared every ward he possibly could on the door and turned to begin his work. No more hesitating.

Outside the door, Bellatrix could feel magic building up to protect the room - and then nothing. The huge force was all washed out.

He must be working on his device, I can see why he wouldn't want to be interrupted, that would be delicate work. Could it be possible that he can create this device, as he spoke of it? He would have had to learn some deep magical secret, but knowing Tom, this is more than possible...

Terence Keen gave Bellatrix an odd look as he walked past.

"Tom's in the library."

He stopped, confused. "I wasn't looking for Tom."

"Well he's in the library, do you want me to take you to him?"

Keen snorted. "Oh... the library, right, that's good to know." The boy took a step closer. "Come on, what type of blood magic is he really practicing in there?"

Bellatrix's eyes widened. She had to stop him!

"If he's practicing blood magic, do you think it's smart to be speaking so openly about it?"

He should have just minded his own business in the first place.

"Merlin… You're serious aren't you?" Keen turned pale.

"Am I?" Bellatrix put a sweet edge into her voice. "Even if he was sacrificing a bunch of squirrels, it wouldn't be any of your business."

"No, I suppose not..." He looked at Tom's door once more and then walked away, rather quickly. Bella smirked and settled in with a book.

After a time, the rat-faced boy reappeared and handed Bellatrix a small pouch. "Look, I don't even want payment for that. Tell Riddle I don't want to be involved in any of this anymore, and I won't be helping him again."

Bellatrix put the pouch in her robes and waited for Tom to emerge, as she wouldn't interrupt whatever was going on inside the room.

It was perhaps another hour before she felt the wards break; she stood up to attention as Tom opened the door.

His robes were fresh, but he was still sweating and looking pale and tired. "Do you have the package?"

She pulled it out of her robes. "I do. Tom, are you Ok? Just what did you-"

"It iss no concern of yourss!" Tom seemed to hiss at her as he reached out, nearly snatching the pouch from her before he put it in his own pocket.

"I need to leave the school now for a short time and deliver this." Tom said, rather quickly, "You will continue to convince people I am present but unaccounted for at the moment, is that clear?"

"Yes." Bellatrix nodded vigorously.

"Did anybody ask after me while I was inside?" Tom asked her.

"Not really, Keen was looking for you but I told him you weren't here and he left."

"Good." Tom walked away without even bothering to ward his room again, so Bellatrix laid a few charms on the door and went on her way. What in Merlin's name is he up to?

As Tom turned the corner into the main common room, he stopped short, as it seemed everybody was staring at him. He wasn't being paranoid, they were in fact looking at him, and he didn't like the way they were whispering.

"Bellatrix…" Tom thought, instantly regretting involving her in any way at all. He walked towards the exit, ignoring the looks. He couldn't help but hear the whispers though.

"squirrels?"

"blood"?

"ritual"?

As he made his way across the room, it only made him more confused.

Tom left the common room and started down the hallway, and saw Headmaster Dippet and Professor Dumbledore were coming towards him.

What? No! They can't know anything! Stay calm...

Headmaster Dippet was looking rather sheepish when he said, "Mister Riddle, I'm afraid you're going to have to come with us and answer some questions. I've received some alarming reports as to your activities."

Tom looked at Dumbledore; the man was looking rather severe, and stood just a few feet in front of the Headmaster. Ha, Dippet won't approach me alone.

Oh.

Wait.

That's not... actually good...

Chapter 9

Chapter Nine

Side-Along Apparition was stressful at the best of times, but Tom was quite proud that he managed to hold out from vomiting even after arriving at Tobo Mott's. He just managed to take a few steps toward a chair before falling over and passing out again on the floor.

When he woke, he found himself in a bed, dirty clothes replaced with a clean set of robes. All of the devices and objects he had worn concealed lay on the table beside him, along with a large glass of water. A light orange mist appeared to be floating down on him from above, like a light rain, though Tom couldn't feel any moisture.

It seems Tobo has taken this opportunity to practice his nursing skills.

Tobo opened the door softly, but it still creaked. "Thank Merlin, you're awake!" He walked over to Tom and began fussing over him. "You must be thirsty. Aguamenti!" The spell streamed water from Tobo's wand to Tom's mouth, and as the spell basically drew pure water from air, Tom had no compunctions in drinking it. Besides, he was rather thirsty.

"Are you quite comfortable? Do you need any more pillows? I've got tea and soup on the boil. Can you sit up?"

Tom frowned at him and did so. "Where's my wand?"

Tobo lifted the edge of his left sleeve, his off-arm, to show an extra wand and holster that Tom instantly recognized. "Didn't think it'd be safe for you to cast anything after you'd been drained."

Tom addressed the issue that would be bothering Tobo the most.

"I am sure your Patronus will not suffer ill effects, nor will you."

Tobo scoffed, "And what of you? Surely you've been affected…"

Tom waved the comment off. "Yes, but since I ate the Patronus I believe that I will be completely fine soon enough."

"And how can you know that?"

Tom turned up the corners of his mouth. "I know, because I will make it so."

"You keep saying that you ate the Patronus. What on Earth does that mean?"

This, then, was the reason Tobo was puttering around full of nervous energy.

"Well. I touched it, and I seem to have absorbed something from it. I assume it was the bit of magic you used to cast it." Tom considered that for a moment, then continued. "You've never been drained like that? Well, it was awful. The world felt dull, as though I was missing a sense. I had no magical power to speak of, nor could I sense it anywhere else. Until the Patronus arrived. That, I could feel the magic radiating from; it just all seemed extremely obvious once I saw it. I took its magic for myself and it seems to have jump started me again." Tom trailed off, wondering if it would be possible to experiment further. Tobo would clearly not want to, but surely some other students were capable of casting it.

Looking back up at Tobo, he went on. "Now, I admit I know little of the spell but it seems to me that a person shouldn't simply be able to 'eat' one, so to speak, and take something from the caster." Tom tapped his cheek with his finger. "I wonder, what exactly did you tell it to do?"

The rough man seemed to freeze for a moment, and he looked away from Tom before speaking. "I told it to deliver the message. I told it you were in trouble, and asked it to help in any way it could… I didn't really think it could do anything besides relay the message and project your location for me."

So it interpreted that to mean...?

Tom knew you had to mean it when you cast the Patronus. So - Tobo actually cared for him? In some way, at least. Enough to not kill him when he couldn't defend himself, at least. Tom didn't think he could count on the man to never try to kill him, but at the very least, Tobo found him useful.

"What can you tell me of the magic used to strike me down?" Tom asked, breaking himself from the strange feeling he had momentarily.

Tobo shrugged. "Nothing I've heard of before. But I think you were extremely lucky." The man gestured out of the bedroom. Tom could just see the stone table where Darius Ahlee was now awake, invisibly bound in an awkward position and deaf to the conversation.

"If this one had finished whatever curse that was, I suspect the effects would have been permanent, or fatal." His voice had a strange sad quality to it, which faded as he went on, "Guess you learned the hard way that you aren't adult yet." A forced laugh. "Aye, you survived. Just barely, but I will give you credit for that achievement."

Tom felt his temper rising, and managed to sit up as he threw back the blankets. "Not only did I survive, but I completed a series of tasks, which you yourself could not. As a result, I have delivered you your enemy for interrogation, and any other fun games you want to play with him."

Tom was now angry as he continued, but the air pressure wasn't pressing down on the room like it should have been. "In addition to the wizard himself, you now are in possession of his device of power."

For now.

Tobo let out a sarcastic laugh as he looked over to the stone mantle where he had placed it in some type of force field.

"Hah… The moment I touched it I could feel it calling to me. 'Put me on, Put me ON!' it was like. I don't trust that for a moment. It shouldn't have to urge me to wear it; I think it wants to kill me."

Tom suppressed a smile. If that was true, certain steps must be necessary to claim it as its master. If anyone could find these steps, Tom could. But he simply said, "A fair assumption."

"As for myself - what have your diagnostic spells revealed to you?" Tom demanded of the man.

"It's like you said, you definitely lost your magic for a time. Now it's returning slowly. Though... I wouldn't get your hopes up. Dark magic of that caliber normally has lasting effects; you may never be as strong as you were."

Not only will I reach that peak again, but I will surpass it by miles.

Tobo looked away. "Hell, I knew a man who was struck by a powerful dark curse once…"

"What happened to him?" Tom prompted.

"Nothing happened immediately. I mean, the sky turned purple, and a streak of black light broke from a cloud, it seemed to pierce his heart. Yet he still struck down his foe and walked away just fine. In fact, he seemed fine for the next several years, until he started hearing voices in his head commanding him to do things, like he was under Imperius." Tobo shuddered. "Anyone who listened, he'd say, 'They told me to drown my wife! They told me to burn my son!' Even to the Dementors."

Tom flinched at the word, but he was reminded of something. "A Patronus is considered to be one of the purest magic's. It will hold back the evil of a dementor, after all. For the lack of a better term, it would be what people consider 'Light' magic, isn't that right?"

Tobo frowned, "Aye… I suppose you could say that. I was surprised to learn that I could perform the spell, considering most people would consider me a 'Dark Wizard'."

"Perhaps, in some cases, the light may wash away the dark? That sounds like the sort of poetic rhythm that fundamental magic seems to work on." As Tom said it he felt it for truth: intuition, but his intuition was generally pretty accurate about magic.

Tobo let a real laugh escape his lips this time. "Perhaps. That sounds more like the moral of some story tale than how life works though."

I agree.However, in this instance I believe I am onto something.

"Tobo, how did you come to learn how to cast the Patronus charm? I would agree with your assumption that you shouldn't be able to." Tom knew that would sound like an insult to most people.

"My son…" Tobo whispered.

Tom could see Tobo tense up, so he didn't reply. Instead he sat and waited for more information about this apparent son Tobo had. Not that he really cared about the man's son, but apparently it was relevant to the Patronus discussion.

"My son, Stefford, was a great man. Better than I ever was, in every way. When I say he was a great man, I'm not just saying that as his father, he did things that…" Tobo cut himself off. "Well. It doesn't matter… Point is, when I saw him use the lessons I taught him, he easily overthrew a small group of terrorists in magical London… I felt something that I knew I could use to cast the spell…"

Tobo seemed to be finished, but Tom probed further. "What is it that you felt?"

The old man seemed to age a decade as he frowned sadly at Tom.

Tobo began to walk out of the room. Tom tried to stand up, failed, and fell back into the bed. By the time he had rearranged himself, Tobo had returned with two small vials, a blue and a red one.

Tom immediately tensed up at the sight. He hadn't felt this vulnerable in a long time, not since the orphanage when he thought he was a Muggle. But he waited for Tobo to say something.

"Red is for magical exhaustion, perhaps it will help kick start a faster recovery. If recovery is possible, that is."

Oh, nicely done.Make it seem like a long shot.A sure thing would be far too obvious.

Tom remained quiet, simply staring at the vials.

"The blue will put you to sleep for a time to recover your physical strength. In addition with the red, you should be strong enough to go back to school once you wake up. I'd not recommend fighting any powerful wizards for a while."

Hmm…The theory is right, and the potions look consistent with what he claims them to be…

"I've already missed a day of classes, I can explain that, but I shouldn't press it."

Tobo put the potions on the bedside table. "How will you explain losing 90% of your power over a weekend? Knowing you, I fully expect every Hogwarts student to know of your abilities."

You do not know me so well then.They have no clue what I am capable of, why would I advertise my true strength and lose the advantage of surprise?

"I won't. The more you allow yourself to be questioned, the more people think they have the right to question you," Tom said with a tone of finality.

Tobo shrugged. "Fine, my stores are running low anyway. If you don't want them, I'll keep them for myself."

Tom looked over to the potion bottles and sighed.

I don't think he wants to kill me…Not yet anyways.

Tom tried to summon the bottles to his open hand with a mere gaze, but it failed.

Tobo removed the wand from the holster and gave it back to him. "If you insist on casting, do it right.

Tom grimaced. "Accio potions." They slowly lifted up and came towards him; he had time to reattach the holster and put his wand away before reaching back up to grab them.

The state I'm in is absolutely pathetic, I feel as though I am a helpless boy again.

Tom opened the red bottle first and raised it to his lips, watching Tobo the entire time. The man wasn't even paying attention, instead he was back to reading the book of advanced interrogation techniques that Tom's foe had to look forward to.

Tom gulped the potion down in one swig. He immediately felt a small rush, as though he had been dunked in cold water suddenly, but it was pleasant. He did the same with the second bottle and started to feel woozy. I hope this produces dreamless sleep…

/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*

When Tom awoke again he felt much better, stronger.

Still weak…Less so than before, but this is almost shameful.

He figured he had enough problems at the moment, and didn't want to add splinching to the list, so he decided to walk back to school.

"Do you want me to walk with you, at least part of the way?" Tobo asked as Tom was preparing to leave.

Tom stopped, "Do you anticipate retribution for the capture of the dark wizard?"

"What? No… I mean, nobody worth thinking about will care." Tobo seemed thrown off by the question. "I was just asking if you wanted…" Tobo sighed. "Never mind son, go on."

"What of our agreement?" Tom looked at Tobo hard. "I believe I was to receive something in return for this task…"

Tobo's eyes widened.

"Are you kidding? I was worried you might not be strong enough to learn that curse to begin with, now…" He trailed off. "Look, we'll work something out. You did well by me, and I will return the favor, as I always have."

Tom knew the best way to regain his strength was to push himself to a new limit. On top of his uncanny natural ability to wield the forces of magic, it was his use of powerful magic with delicate precision that made him stronger, with practice and focus keeping him that way.

I doubt there is any way to convince him that a literal trial by fire is the way to go now.I will not let him forget our deal though.

As soon as Tom was in the street, he raised his hand and flicked his wrist in a well-practiced motion. Yet his wand did not appear as it should have.

"Accio wand!"

He flicked his wrist again, this time pushing his magic into his hand as he thought it. The wand came loose from the holster down his sleeve and flew into his hand, though it brought him little satisfaction.

That was slow; people will see the trick of it unless the wand just appears to be in my hand.

Tom took few deep breaths and let the annoyance wash away, it was clouding his mind.

As he walked, he practiced his summoning charm over and over using his wand and thought alone, taking only a little satisfaction in not having to utter the words. He had always taken pride in his wandless and wordless magic; having to use a wand to summon light bits of trash was degrading.

"Accio paper bag!" He thought as he gestured with the yew wand, and a paper bag flew towards him as if it were caught on a strong draft.

Tom kept his wand trained on the bag as it approached.

STOP

He hadn't used any spell; he had simply focused his magic and forced it out. The paper bag stopped right in front of him and floated there.

Tom visualized flashes of fire, orange and white flames, throwing sparks, burning rapidly.

The paper bag flashed up in a quick burst of flame and was gone. That made Tom smile. Fire often made him smile.

By the time Tom reached the Shrieking Shack, High Street was cleaner than it had ever been - not a single stray candy wrapper was spared.

/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*

Tom arrived at school with still a couple hours until breakfast. He figured he had better go and explain himself to the Headmaster before people actually started to wonder what he was truly up to.

As he made his way towards the Headmaster's office, he was constantly pushing outwards, letting his magic flow and resonate with the area around him. It was a vastly difficult thing to do at the moment, compared to the effortless instinct he had before. It didn't seem to be working all that well either, as he came up on Myrtle sitting against a wall in the corridor as he turned the corner. Then again, he almost never noticed her, visually or magically. In all senses, she was too weak to register.

"Tom!" The girl stood when she saw him, smiling her repulsive grin. She began to run over to him, but when he raised a hand in protest, she instantly stopped, her smile disappearing and her shoulders slumping.

"Hello, Myrtle," Tom said, hoping that would be the extent of this conversation.

"Tom, I haven't slept all night! I'm so scared, Tom!" Myrtle exclaimed.

What is it now?Did your shadow spook you?

"Go to bed till breakfast, you'll feel better after you sleep and eat." Tom took a step forward and to the left to get past her in order to signify the exchange was over.

Insensitive as ever, Myrtle stepped in front of him. At least, he hoped it was her poor social skills, and not insolence. "I've been staying here outside the Headmaster's office all night. I don't know the password to get in, but I'm sure that the gargoyle will let me up if I'm in danger."

"Do you think so?" In spite of himself, Tom was interested. Although he probably wouldn't have been, if he himself hadn't needed to see the Headmaster. He didn't particularly care what danger Myrtle thought she was in, but he decided that unless he killed her, he was going to have to hear her out. Turning back to her, he tried to sound concerned. "Why would you be in danger, Myrtle?"

From the beginning of the sentence, she appeared relaxed, but the word "danger" seemed to remind her that she was in a panic. "The monster chased me!" she said, offering no other explanation.

Tom was confused, this was the first he had heard of a monster in the school. As far as he knew, the wards were quite good at keeping those types of things out, and certainly, Dumbledore wouldn't stand for a monster in the school.

Unless…!

Tom's breath caught in his chest.

A monster designed by Salazar Slytherin himself…

Tom nearly lost his composure and grabbed the girl to demand answers, but he managed to hold himself together. He waited a moment more just to be sure he was calm and collected, then said, "Start at the beginning, and tell me absolutely everything, Myrtle, so I can help you."

Myrtle smiled widely at that and moved a step closer, and Tom automatically took a step back at the same time.

"It's the monster that's running around at night trying to eat kids! I didn't believe it at first, but then I was walking to bed last night, and it came around the corner and chased me!" She exclaimed, all in one breath.

Tom was losing enthusiasm fast. This sounds like the same nonsense the Headmaster was accusing me of…Clearly nobody really thinks there's a monster with an appetite for children.

"You saw it then?" Tom pressed.

"No, I heard it. I came around a corner downstairs, and all of a sudden, I heard something scrambling after me. I ran to the bathroom, and it chased me halfway there before it disappeared." Myrtle had tears in her eyes from recalling her fear. She perked up a little though and said, "That bathroom always feels so safe. It felt especially safe when I was in there after the chase. I just knew in my heart the monster wouldn't chase me in there."

Tom didn't see how a bathroom could be considered safe, with only one entry/exit and tight quarters to fight in, but he didn't press the issue.

Clearly those seventh year idiots think that chasing students around at night constitutes a prank now…It's a shame how far the prank squad has fallen.

It seemed obvious to Tom. The practical jokers of the seventh year were certainly capable of trickery realistic enough to put true fear in younger students. It wasn't as if they were above this sort of thing either; this year's bunch of "pranksters" was poor quality.

When I'm in seventh year, perhaps I'll simply take over and redefine the group. Give it a real purpose, real goals…Though there's no rule that says I can't do that in my fifth year, even if there was it shouldn't apply to me.

Snapping back to reality, he said, "Myrtle, have you been talking with any seventh-years lately, or perhaps the Burke brother in our year?"

She shook her head. "No, I don't talk to many people… They always-"

Tom cut her off, "I doubt there is any monster, Abigail. I think somebody is playing a joke on you and several other students. I do not know why, but I intend to find out."

Myrtle shrunk a little at first, "A joke, of course it is. It always is…" Then the second part of the statement registered. "You'd do that for me Tom?" She was full of admiration.

"Certainly," he replied. Although it wasn't exactly for her, he simply hated school-wide plots that he knew nothing of. Tom waved his hand to dismiss her and said, "Go now - to your bathroom if you feel safer - but go and no harm will come to you. I do not think you need to bother the Headmaster with this."

The girl seemed a great deal calmer now. "Thanks Tom! I feel so safe with you looking out for me!" She smiled at him for a long awkward moment, and then turned and left.

Tom pushed the childish plot from his mind, and focused on the task at hand. He had to speak with the Headmaster and defuse any suspicion that may have come from his absence.

When he approached the gargoyle he didn't think it would be as easy as asking politely, but he tried anyways.

"Excuse me for coming at such an early hour. I have urgent business to discuss with the Headmaster."

That of course failed to produce any results, which made Tom glad. With this prank and/or monster going on, it would have been highly disappointing if one could get into the Headmaster's office simply by asking. But was Myrtle's theory any better? He tapped his cheek, thinking. Not only would it be counterproductive to stage some dangerous scenario simply to explain an absence, a proper security system would simply alert the Headmaster, rather than opening the door.

So Tom started casting magic at the statue, a random spell here and there, but mostly he was just using his own raw magic with no real spell behind it to strike at the statue.

He quickly became winded and stopped to rest.

Suddenly, Headmaster Dippet's voice echoed out of the gargoyle's mouth. "What are you doing, Tom Riddle?"

"I was merely trying to get your attention, Sir. I'd like to have a word with you, if I could."

The gargoyle yawned and said, "I imagine you would have said if it was an emergency. So allow me a few moments to get ready."

The statue became still once more and Tom was left to wait.

Once he was granted entry to the office, he made his way forward to the desk and stood before it.

"I'm not sure if you or any of my professors have noticed, but I was not present in my classes yesterday. Nor will I attend today, and I want to explain," Tom said with a slight tone of shame.

"Professor Dumbledore did in fact notice that you were missing. When he could neither find you in your dorm or the hospital wing he was quite concerned," Dippet replied.

Concerned about what I was getting up to, you mean.

Tom was unsettled; this wasn't the first time he had missed a transfiguration class, but it was apparently the first time Dumbledore actively tried to find out why.

"Well, no, sir, he wouldn't have found me there. I was in Hogsmeade, studying with a professional tutor. After all, if I try to hide away in the school, people will start spreading rumors and disrupting me," Tom said stiffly, referring to his previous summons to the office.

"A professional tutor you say?" Dippet seemed intrigued. "Who is it?"

"Nobody you'd know sir, just somebody who was helping me prepare for my Defense against the Dark Arts OWL."

Dippet frowned. "Mister Riddle, I know that you don't approve of the way classes are taught here at Hogwarts. But you cannot simply come and go as you please! Hogwarts classes are to be the first priority."

If by disapprove you mean I think 90% of classes are a waste of time, which could be used to really learn magic, I'll agree with that.

"I know, sir. It's not going to be a habit; it was just the one day of study. But I'm afraid it has left me rather worn out. I'd like permission to skip my classes today as well so I can get some rest."

"Well, if you're that worn out, you'd best go to the Infirmary."

"Yes sir, thank you, Sir," Tom said and left the office.

The Infirmary was less than ideal but he decided it would help sell the story. His entire body ached, and he wanted a proper breakfast, but he couldn't look forward to going to the Great Hall. In the hospital wing, he'd be waited on hand and foot by the spinster Nurses who thought he was a handsome young man, but they'd know better than to bother him.

So he went to his room, took out all the books he wanted, and headed to the Infirmary.

Chapter 11

Chapter 11

Idly tapping his cheek, Tom was sitting at his desk, looking down at the pages of the old potions book.

That might do. If done correctly it should all seem very natural.

He committed the relevant text to memory before closing the book, then walked to his trunk, but hesitated to replace it in its hiding spot. Should he burn the book instead? The hidden compartment would only react to his own wand, true, but couldn't they take it from him? He wouldn't put it past Dumbledore to look everywhere, if it came to light that such a plot existed. Assuming that he could really hide anything from Dumbledore was foolish, even back at full strength...

Yet, burning the book and vanishing the ashes seemed like a true crime. Silly things like blackmail or appropriate killings were irrelevant. Burning this valuable book would actually be a crime. There was little if any chance of ever replacing it, and even if he never truly needed the book again in his life, it was always better to be able to read a book than not.

I'm going to need an appropriate hiding place outside of the school for my more valuable things. I should have had one already, it's foolish to assume my wards can't be broken into.

Tom set the book down on his bed, considered, then set his wand down beside it. He then leaned forward and performed the appropriate rites that opened the hidden drawer of the trunk. It contained a couple of books and a few more questionable items: ward-breaking glasses, maps of a few of the known passages out of the school, his spare invisibility cloak, and one of those ridiculous fanged Frisbee's.

Tom looked at the Frisbee for a moment and let out a small chuckle. Anyone who did find the hidden compartment would not look twice, the toy was against the rules, and that was why it was hidden. Unless they happened to think about why Tom Riddle would have a novelty toy. Against the rules, yes, but not at all something Riddle would have owned. He pulled it from the drawer and held it up in front of his eyes.

"A wizard isn't born into the world possessing magic; rather he is born into a world full of magic to possess."

Marwyn's writing. He let the forming incantation slip from his mind. There was magic all around him, the stones of the castle themselves heated the air with a faint tingle of magic.

Tom let go of the Frisbee as he closed his eyes, and it floated perfectly still in front of him.

Fire… There was fire in the room; the torches on the wall had inherent power that most people would never realize. The room seemed to heat up a few degrees at the thought.

Tom simply pictured ghostly translucent flames being drawn from thin air toward the toy, and suddenly he felt the heat.

He opened his eyes and smiled as he watched it burn up into nothing, as the device let out a quiet but pained scream. That made Tom laugh out loud, and he found himself with a new appreciation for whoever created the toy. Perhaps he should get another after all.

He returned his gaze to the apparent last drawer of his trunk. Closed his eyes briefly, and sensed nothing. Not being able to even detect your own enchantments was a very good sign; the concealment seemed secure. Then again, the school seemed secure; Tom knew all too well that security could be exploited.

He felt around the bottom of the drawer, pushing things aside to rub his fingers along the seams. Ignoring the texture of wood on his fingers he focused on any note of lingering magic he could find.

I can't even feel it; there is no way to open it. The contents will burn up if any serious tampering happens.

But was that really good enough? Tom had apparently been playing too fast and loose. It seemed he had Dumbledore's attention now, and leaving any sort of loose ends within his grasp would be a mistake.

No matter, nothing significant enough has happened to warrant this type of paranoia yet. There is plenty of time to cover my tracks once things are in motion.

Tom resolved to continue trusting in his hidden drawer for the moment, but to find a suitable place where he could hide anything he didn't want to have to destroy.

He grabbed his wand from his bed and pressed it to the bottom of the drawer, which gave off a faint blue glow as it lifted from place to reveal a much larger hidden compartment. He had already put Ancient Secrets back where it was accompanied by half a dozen other books with which he wouldn't want to be caught. Tom carefully placed Potions of Old into the compartment and took a quick mental inventory of what he had.

The contents could raise a lot of questions, and somebody who cares to investigate properly could put me into some hot water…

Tom thought about what conclusions one might draw from the contents as he picked up the .45 semi-automatic pistol from the corner. He pressed the button to drop the magazine and check it to make sure that it was still fully loaded and hadn't been tampered with. He then pulled the slide back in one smooth practiced motion and caught the ejected cartridge.

Tom stood and spun on his heel, swinging the pistol towards the door. He stopped with the sights directly lined up with the center of the frame, and he pulled the trigger three times in quick succession, click click click.

With a smirk he re-inserted the magazine and replaced it among the books, vials of multi colored potions, bracelets, rings and some other fun things that might prove useful.

After resealing the drawer, he took a seat on his bed. He planned to leave a couple hours after curfew, when all the boring people were confined to their dorms, to explore the school and whatever happenings may or may not be happening. He was fairly sure he knew what to expect: Burke and his goons, going about scaring children who wandered the halls, calling it an "epic prank". Unless having a number of scared children was a necessary component to some larger plot, having been called into question over something so mundane was contemptible.

What if it is a part of a larger plot? I hardly believe those morons are capable of stringing things together with any type of proper execution, but...

It all seemed like harmless pranks, reports of children chased off by a terrifying monster with no actual attacks or even real sightings. That could be a good cover up for something else, something darker. The administration certainly wasn't taking it too seriously, so a competent Dark wizard could hide nefarious goings on with an innocent explanation. Of course, he was the only competent Dark wizard among the student body - not that everyone else wasn't Dark, just not capable of what he was seeing. On the other hand, the Professors were more powerful, but he didn't think any of them were Dark. But that could just be prejudice. If it was a teacher, any of them had more access to the school, and more clout to get away with -

Tom shook his head. Then suddenly it struck him, if it was indeed a professor, one of them could be trying to get people upset only to "resolve" the situation later, in a grand heroic fashion.

But who? Professor Merrythought? He had a slow-cooking plot to sabotage her reputation, but she hardly could seem more secure in her position. Still, on a quick skim of the staff, she would be the most likely to do something like that.

Then again, not everything was a plot orchestrated by some master player. As much as he wished life worked like that, more times than not he had to work to get himself involved in any interesting activities.

What if there truly is some monster running around the school at night?

Tom had to at least consider the surface story. It seemed ridiculous; there were wards against that type of thing, he knew all too well. Any creature that could be dangerous to the students shouldn't be able to get in without alarm.

In theory. In practice, Tom had found quite a few loopholes in the wards, and he hadn't even considered exploiting the magical creature wards. Still, even if you could bring in something dangerous, why expose it by letting it scare children?

Tom wiped his face. Thinking about it was all well and good, but no one could enumerate every possibility in the short time left before he was going to go and actually find out for himself. He was feeling a bit more wary, now, though. Especially as he was probably as powerful as an average third year at the moment.

Tobo would surely say that his recovery was going remarkably well, all things considered. Tom himself was unsatisfied; he had given up his Muggle weight training because he didn't have the patience for the slow results. He certainly wouldn't give up his magical training, but it had to happen more rapidly.

After his Animagus transformation, he had nearly depleted himself, but it had rushed back like a tidal wave, boosting him to a new apparent plateau. It had been incredible for the short time he was wielding his might against a powerful foe. He would not be satisfied until he not only reached that peak again, but surpassed it.

Even if he was capable of transforming to a snake right now, it would do him no good. The actual effort of the first transformation had pushed him over some edge. There had to be other ways to expedite the process…

If I did get out of the castle and transform, I could hunt a unicorn… I'm not near death but it would likely restore my power.

Tom frowned and put the idea aside, he hardly needed more darkness start surrounding him at the moment. He could barely remember his brief scuffle with Monroe, since at the time he had hardly considered his actions, going off reflex, intuition.

"Oh, damn," he said softly. Monroe was a prefect, after all, what if they ran into each other tonight? After all, it would hardly be surprising to see Monroe bullying scared children. If only the boy wasn't so bloody infuriating! The hostility between them really had to come down to a more reasonable level, and that wouldn't happen if they interacted tonight. He would simply avoid him, no matter what. Anyone else who saw him, he'd just say that since he had slept most of the day, he was restless. That should end any questions or line of conversation.

After exiting his room, Tom warded his door quickly and walked towards the common room. A single person remained in the large room; Tom mentally kicked himself for thinking Monroe was the only person who could press his buttons.

Bellatrix Black was sitting in a chair near the fire, holding a book. Facing Tom.

"Bellatrix. I had hoped that of all people, you would know better than to try and poke your nose in my business. Yet I cannot look at a mirror without seeing your head clumsily darting out of view."

Bellatrix tried to seem taken aback. "I was not waiting for you!"

"I never said you were waiting for me. But, why were you waiting for me, Bella?"

Bellatrix stood up, the glare of the fire reflected in her eyes. Except that she wasn't facing the flames.

"I thought you'd want to know, Monroe is in the hospital wing! His girlfriend cursed him somehow, and broke two of his ribs!" She exclaimed with brief enthusiasm before calming to watch Tom's reaction.

Well, I did kick him from a full sprint… I probably should have considered healing him a little. I can't believe he would degrade himself by saying that he was defeated by a small girl, when he could have said he'd stood up to Tom Riddle! He could have even had me brought in front of Dippet... He must be afraid of me. Of course he is, but these seem to be actions that say "I've had enough Tom, you win." Or, it's a feint. Does he plan to strike in some other way perhaps?

Tom noticed that Bellatrix was still staring at him.

"Very good Bella, that is indeed humorous," he said, turning and walking away. After a few steps, he could tell Bellatrix was following him. He turned to her again and snapped, "Are you lost?"

Bellatrix's blank expression changed significantly and she sighed. "Yeah, I guess you could say that…" With that she turned and made her way towards the stairs.

Strange girl… Though I will need to make use of her soon, it's a bad idea but I will approach it differently this time. Leave no room for misinterpretation or error on her part.

Tom shook his head at the difficulty that would present. He pushed that thought aside and started out on his way.

If I was the average Hogwarts student trying to play shady games in the night I might consider the dungeons as an appropriate staging ground. I can also have a preliminary talk with Slughorn while I am down there. It will need to be done carefully, very natural and unassuming. I can't draw attention to the real question.

/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*

Professor Slughorn leaned away from the pewter cauldron and wiped the sweat from his brow; it would do no good to let his fluids taint the work.

"Three turns widdershins…" he recited from memory.

"Seventeen seconds of simmering… fifteen, fourteen..." He counted down to zero, when he emptied a vial of crushed leaves into the mixture and mashed them in carefully with a special wooden fork.

*Tap Tap Tap*

"One moment!" Slughorn shouted to the door behind him as he swirled the potion from the center outwards, counting nine turns. The potion turned from a pale orange to a thick pus-colored fluid. The Professor extinguished the flames, admired the potion for a moment, and then turned to go to his door.

"Oh, hello Mr. Riddle. I had heard you were ill, shouldn't you be in bed so you're prepared for classes tomorrow?"

The boy smirked at him. "Have no fear, sir, I'm always prepared for classes. Are classes prepared for me might be the better question."

"Ah hah hah!" Slughorn forced a laugh. The boy's arrogance was often amusing, and sometimes unsettling.

It was said that Tom had been exhausted from extensive study, so much so that he had missed classes today. Yet the boy looked more than fine. His mere presence seemed to dim the torches on the wall and cool the air, as though he drew power from it all.

Over his years of teaching and personally knowing many powerful wizards, Professor Slughorn had an intuition for which students would do great things. He knew that Tom Riddle was a student with unmistakeable potential.

"What can I do for you, ?" Slughorn asked, stepping from the doorway as Tom walked in.

Tom walked in a few paces and sniffed the air. "That is foul, Professor."

"Ah, yes it should be… You know, I think I burned out my nose long ago, Mr. Riddle." Slughorn sniffed the air and detected only the faintest odor.

"I haven't," Tom said, sounding near annoyed. The boy pointed to the far end of the room with his finger and swept his hand across to the door as though he was ushering somebody out. As he gestured, a moderate breeze carried all of the smoke and fumes out the door and down the hallway.

Slughorn blinked at that, and suddenly Tom's face was back to that of a calm and collected young man.

Tom walked over to the cauldron and looked in.

"Careful, Mr. Riddle!" Slughorn said as he reached out to draw Tom away. He hesitated, however, and let his arm fall back to his side.

"You don't want to get any of that on you, my boy!"

Tom observed the potion for a long moment and then stepped back. "No, I expect not… Just what are you up to, Professor?" The boy cocked his head curiously as he looked into the professors eyes.

"Ah… Well you see, that is a potion for-"

"An extreme case of near untreatable itchy boils." Tom finished for him easily.

Slughorn froze for a moment in fear. "Ha, ha well Tom, I guess I wasn't going to fool you by saying it was for growing hair… Even though the two are identical in smell, and close enough in color."

Tom waited a moment before speaking. "The length of your 'moment' before you came to the door was far too short for it to be a follicle regeneration potion. That final step is forty-four turns, and a three minute simmering. But the fire was out when I came in. "

Slughorn was taken aback. "Merlin save us! You really pieced it together from that?"

Tom smirked for a moment and then sighed. "I'd love to say yes, but that only occurs to me now. Truthfully, I am familiar with this potion, and I noticed the faint orange swirls, which appear infrequently along the sides."

"Oh." Slughorn replied, dazed.

"But I actually wanted to have a conversation with you, sir," Tom said before he turned away from the potion and took a seat on top of a desk at the front of the classroom. He gestured for the professor to take a seat at his own desk.

Professor Slughorn was happy to oblige, and avoid any questions about why he was brewing such a nasty potion on his off time.

"So Tom, what is it that I can help you with?" Slughorn pulled back his chair and took a seat at his large oak desk. He didn't fail to notice that he had to look up at the boy sitting on top of his own desk.

"Well sir, I spent today reading mostly, and I came across some interesting potions. Some of which I wouldn't believe existed, except for the fact that their creation seems plausible under the right circumstances."

Slughorn chuckled, "Ah yes, there are some curious ones." He leaned back and thought for a moment. "Felix Felicis comes to mind instantly. If we are to believe 'liquid luck' ever existed, then we are to believe that the potion literally created itself through sheer luck. One version of the tale has an earthquake knocking a certain ingredient off the shelf into a pot of poorly homebrewed fire whiskey. It then shook the ingredients together just right. Then, the would-be drunkard just happened to decide to use a special freezing charm on the potion and the fire in his kitchen."

He chuckled again. "He didn't understand the effects. He knew he was lucky, but he kept testing it in insane ways. They say he ran around for days chasing thunder storms. He would stand in the open as he watched lightning strike birds landing near him, or confused people who wandered over to ask him for directions to the quidditch world cup."

Tom's face was blank. "What do they say happened to him?"

Slughorn shrugged. "His luck ran out I suppose! He was struck by several bolts at once during one of his experiments. It would seem almost as though the storms were taking vengeance on being manipulated." That idea made him laugh.

Tom did not laugh; instead a serious look came over his face as he seemed to consider the idea for a moment. He then looked up. "That is a good one, sir, though I've heard of an even more interesting one. Very creative, the witch who made it was a genius. She managed to save her own life by creating it in a single week with nothing but knowledge and purpose."

"Hmm, I'm not sure I am familiar with this, Tom, do go on."

"Well sir, I hope you're not squeamish." He looked back towards the cauldron. When he looked to the professor again he had that smirk on his face again. "The potion does involve blood as the main component…"

Slughorn lit up at that. "Ah yes, now I remember. That tale is even more fascinating than the luck potion, because we know it to be true! It was a shame how it all turned out in the end, very messy affair…"

/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*/*

Tom left the office feeling content with his plan; Slughorn had alleviated all of his concerns. Not only that, it had been good timing to walk in on him brewing illegal potions.

He is probably making all kinds of fun things for people with coin… Even if he ends up suspecting me because of that conversation, he knows that I am aware that he has some skeletons in his closet.

Even if he didn't get any clues as to what was happening after dark during his stroll, this had already been an extremely productive evening.

He had been walking for several minutes lost in thought, when suddenly he could feel somebody approaching around the corner.

They must be powerful if I can feel them when I'm this weak…

Tom took a few steps back and moved into the center of the hallway. At the same time, he stretched his wrist back and forth a couple of times to loosen it up for a flawless wand-draw.

A girl came around the corner, a sandy haired 4th year by the look of it. She was briefly startled when she suddenly walked into Tom standing his ground, but the look passed and she seemed annoyed.

"What are you doing?" Tom put authority into his voice.

She flinched momentarily but regained her composure. "What are you doing? You're not a prefect…"

Well she obviously knows who I am; can't return the favor.

"No, that's David Monroe. He apparently was cursed into oblivion by a young girl in a hallway. Maybe it was you?"

The girl laughed at the accusation. "Sam didn't curse him! He just got her angry."

Tom wanted to smile at that. The girl could have easily turned Tom in; she had to know that it was his doing that put Monroe out of commission. She was at least smart enough to keep her mouth shut.

"I ask again, what are you up to at this hour? Miss…."

"Miss Brown."

Tom waited till she sighed and gave up. "I was going to say I have Dippet's permission, but I get the feeling that won't fly…"

Tom nodded in agreement.

"Look, I'm not causing trouble, I just have business outside the school, ok?"

Tom locked onto her gaze to see if she would flinch. Instead, in her eyes he found flashes of a young boy waiting outside the schools wards.

He blinked and the vision was gone; he hadn't really meant to probe her mind.

That came a little too easily.

The girl didn't seem to notice that Tom had just peeked into her mind. He was unsure what to make of her, so he decided to make nothing of her for now.

"Ok, ok. I don't really care what you do." He stepped aside and let her past.

Once she was a dozen paces away, Tom raised his wand, pointed at her boots and closed his eyes. He felt his magic flow out and embed itself in the fabric of the laces in her boots. They seemed to almost glow for a moment, but it faded as she turned a corner. She would never notice, but Tom could get a general idea of where she was tonight if he needed to.

The wards prevented student from tracking each other by all means of which Tom was aware. His magic wouldn't stick on to students themselves, or their wands (which would be the most effective way), or the clothes on their bodies. Yet the laces in their boots were fair game for some bizarre reason.

Tom put it down to a shift in style; the school boots probably didn't have laces in the start when the wards were set in the stones, simply because there's no use for laces in magical boots. Over the years however the style of clothing changed and started incorporating more things just for looks. Every time Tom thought he knew something about the schools wards he just found more questions, so he tried to not think about it too hard right now.

It works, that's all I need to know at the moment.

He continued on his way around the castle, working his way up. Since he had bumped into "Miss Brown," nearly an hour had passed without event. The girl herself had left the wards and not returned, as far as Tom could tell.

Tom was making his way up a staircase when he heard muffled sounds around a corner a couple of floors up. He started to sprint up the stairs, and he caught a glimpse of a giant shape hauling something behind him. It disappeared around a bend, but Tom could still hear strange noises and grunting.

Tom was three steps and one leap away from the landing when the staircase suddenly moved beneath him and started swinging around. He had too much momentum to stop so he kept on, leapt for the ledge, and missed.

As the floor came rushing to meet him, Tom realized he didn't have time to use any magic, so he simply decided to roll into the landing as best he could. He did make the roll, but into a wall, and at a high speed.

Tom had always liked the dark humor in the idea of the moving staircase killing that girl, but he hadn't actually believed it. Now he was certain there was a horrible conspiracy to hide how bloody dangerous this thing was.

One thing at a time now… First of all, what in Merlin's name is that oaf up to? Tom asked himself, as he slowly got up from the ground while wincing from the effort of it.